<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Wilfred Githuka</title>
    <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Wilfred Githuka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 08:43:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjusting Screen Brightness in Linux</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/brightness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 08:43:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/brightness/</guid>
      <description>Brightness is a very important factor when using any device in this mordern age. Many devices produce a large amount of light which is not good to for our eyes. To reduce the amount of light from your device&amp;rsquo;s screen, enable/use a dark theme.
In Linux, screen brightess is rather complex and I hope this brief article will help you understand.
The brightness of the screen backlight is adjusted by setting the power level of the backlight LEDs or cathodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USB Flashdrive, Android Phones Support - This is Thunar</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/filemanager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/filemanager/</guid>
      <description>Lets face it nearly everyone working in an office environment has a flash drive somewhere nearby. They are the common tools for data transfer in the office environment.
At my workplace, its no different. Sometimes a colleague would hand a flashdrive to copy some document and if its urgent, I cannot start mounting it on the terminal, thats not efficient.
I need Thunar.
Thunar is a file manager that comes with XFCE wm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning How to Learn</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/learning-how-to-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/learning-how-to-study/</guid>
      <description>The following article is from [ZiLongShanRen](https://zilongshanren.com/blog/2017-05-09-learning-how-to-learn.html#sec-1-6** which talks about how to learn how to learn.The langauge is good and easy for any HSK 5 and above learner to digest well. The highlighted parts are key grammatical points and new words.
IT 行业是一个变化非常快的行业，它需要我们持续去学习新的知识和技能。 但是，工作以后，我们经常会发现自己学习的东西很少了，倒不是没有时间去学习， 而是学习的效率太低了。久而久之，就演变成『一年的工作经验，重复用十年』。
当然，有些人会说自己经常加班，没有时间学习，这只是表象，时间 挤挤 总是有的。 你想想你为了上王者，浪费了多少时间？为了刷今日头条，又消磨*了多少光阴？
另外，很多人推崇碎片化学习，但是有一些东西碎片化学习效率是很低的，比如数学。
这篇文章是我学习完 Coursera 上面的《Learning How to Learn》MOOC加上我自己多年来的学习经验积累整理而来。
注：文中可能有一些内容思考没有很深入，另外一些观点可能还需要更多的时间去检验，读者请自行甄别。
一些学习的坏习惯 1.1被动反复阅读 通常编程新手在学习一个新东西的时候，喜欢买一本权威指南之类的书（大神或者同事推荐），比如「C++ Primer」和「Javascript 权威指南」。 而这样一本书，一般页数在700-1400页左右，要完整读完，在不求甚解的基础之上大概要花费好几个月甚至大半年时间。 别说是新手，就算是一个C++编程老手去读「Javascript 权威指南」这样的书也不可能在只阅读一遍之后就能理解。 这时，很多人会选择重复多次阅读。有人会从头开始重复阅读，也有人只挑不理解的章节来阅读。 我以前上大学那会儿就是这么干的，读了好多C++的书籍，其实自己编写的C++代码并不多，也没有做过大型的C++项目。 看了好多书，其实都是一知半解，效率很低。工作以后，这种学习方式更加不可取，因为你没有那么多时间这么干。
1.2 喜欢在书上划重点 很多人偏好纸质书，因为在看书的时候手感不错，另外，还可以在书上把喜欢的句子和重点的段落用彩色笔标注出来。 这样做除了给自己造成一种假象「书上的重点我都标出来了，所以我都掌握了」之外，其实并无多大益处。 我现在喜欢在电脑上面看PDF，可以边看边写代码。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minor Issues Unfixed So Far 我的电脑上的小问题</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/problems/</guid>
      <description>The following are some of the issues which remain unsolved so far in my ArchLinux i3 Chinese machine. Some are language specific, some are just system based configuration.
No Chinese Input Support in Spacemacs This is by far the biggest issue am yet to solve. Last year I remeber solving this issue but because I did not document my process, after re-installing Archlinux I have to do it again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs&#43;LaTeX&#43;AuCTeX&#43;CJKutf8 Fonts Problem</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/latex_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/latex_setup/</guid>
      <description>Today is a Monday and I have still not solved the Chinese input on Emacs issue. But I have decided to hold it for a while since I have 2 pending reports to write. I plan to use emacs to write the English version then wps to produce the Chinese version. But today mornning I realised that my latex setup is still not complete. There are some errors during the compilation of AuCTEX to pdf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Cover China, There’s No Substitute for WeChat</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/baodaozhongguo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/baodaozhongguo/</guid>
      <description>This is an article which appeared on the New York Times which talks about the importance and influence Wechat has on the Chinese market. 超过三分之一的人每天在这个应用上花费四个小时或更长时间。 这种普遍程度使微信成为许多人生活和工作中不可或缺的一部分.
The language is easy to understand so this shall be good for matatu reading next time you are on your commute. The English version can be found here
Here we go&amp;hellip;
你会写关中国技术方面的报道。在你的工作中需要依赖哪些技术工具呢，你对它们有什么看法？
可以不夸张地说，我生活在微信里，靠它工作，这个消息应用程序相当于WhatsApp加Facebook加PayPal加优步(Uber)加GrubHub以及许多其他东西。 我的iPhone电池使用记录显示，每天我花9小时使用手机，其中大约三分之一是用在微信上。这还不包括我使用微信web版的那两到三个小时。
像我这样的微信重度使用者不是少数。中国有8亿互联网用户，但有超过10亿的微信账号。几乎每个上网的中国人都至少有一个帐户，有些人不止一个。 超过三分之一的人每天在这个应用上花费四个小时或更长时间。这种普遍程度使微信成为许多人生活和工作中不可或缺的一部分。
两年前，我遇到了两个拒绝使用微信的人，于是我想到，可以写一个关于像这样的人如何驾驭工作和生活的故事。在我抽出时间做这件事之前，这两人都成了我的微信好友。
所以，作为一名记者，我必须待在微信上。我在微信上发消息、和我的信源通话。我对与Facebook时间线类似的微信朋友圈以及群聊保持关注，所以我能总是掌握中国正在发生什么。 当其他人假装很忙而无法回复我时，我会评论他们的朋友圈和群聊，来告诉他们我知道他们并没有那么忙。
到这儿，一些读者肯定在尖叫了，“微信上的审查和政府监控怎么说？”不幸的是，在中国的生活就是这样。我不是要试图淡化这个问题。 我一直很反对科技企业与政府联手审查和监控中国的公众。但现实情况是，普通中国人对审查和监控感到无可奈何，只好听天由命。 我试图说服人们使用Signal、WhatsApp这类加密的消息应用软件，但没什么效果。
我还用微博，中国版的Twitter。我以前是微博活跃用户，上面现在还有几百万粉丝。但几年前政府打击了微博，关停了许多最具挑衅性和影响力的帐户后， 我就不太用了，因为它的话题常常被名人新闻主导，而不是探讨时事.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Input in Emacs on Linux - Attempt 1</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/emacs_chinese_input/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/emacs_chinese_input/</guid>
      <description>Since this year started my Chinese documentation has suffered alot since I don&amp;rsquo;t have Chinese input in Emacs. I use spacemacs as my primary text editor and really need Chinese input.
Fcitx(Flexible Input Method Framework) currently works with the other apps together with Sogou input but not emacs. I seek to find out why. Running fcitx-diagnose says all is okay except for:
 Config GUI for gtk2: Config GUI for gtk2 not found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is It Like To Use Linux In A Chinese Environment</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/linux_in_chinese_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/linux_in_chinese_environment/</guid>
      <description>This is one of those posts I write in a Java Coffee house sipping an expensive cup of tea and wondering why am paying so expensive for milk+tea, but anyway its Java, its expensive because its Java, and the environment is awesome.
So I work at a really great Chinese company called AVIC International, Nairobi. My workmates both Kenyan and Chinese are the best I have met so far in my career, they are quite an undertanding group of lads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review 农民为什么离开土地</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/nongmin_bookreveiew_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/nongmin_bookreveiew_1/</guid>
      <description>书名：农民为什么离开土地 作者：朱启臻，赵晨鸣 主编 出版社：人民日报出版社 出版时间：2011-5-1 版次：1 页数：372 字数：300000 印刷时间：2011-5-1 开本：16开 纸张：胶版纸 印次：1 ISBN：9787511503770 包装：平装  I got hold of this book back in 2014 when I was in Nanjing from Librairie Avant-Garde in Wutaishan. They had a great collection of books and am sure they still have up-to now. I have decided to pick up this book and read it carefully since it shall be good material for my HSK 6 exam which I plan to do in October this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welding Training Graduation</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/graduation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/graduation/</guid>
      <description>Finally after many months (5 months) the training&amp;rsquo;s graduation was held today. The colorful ceremony was helf today at the hall at Kisii National Polytechnic&amp;rsquo;s hall. In attendance was the State Department of Vocational and Technical Education (TVET) together with the other principals who were in attendance, the day was a success.
Even though today was the raduation, we still have another few days of the training to go before we can complete the training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kisumu 基苏木</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/kisumu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/kisumu/</guid>
      <description>After a wonderful time at Sotik, the trainees again organaised a trip to Kisumu to see the city and visit Lake Victoria among other attractions on Saturday the 17th November 2018. This time round the Chinese teachers accompanied us. The day was amazing. I have never been to the lakeside city of Kisumu. Our trainees are drawn from different parts of the country and this time the ones who hailed from Kisumu took us on a tour of the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cover Page(ing) For Your Latex Document</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/cover_page_latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/cover_page_latex/</guid>
      <description>For a while now I have been pondering on how I can add a cover page to my weekly report to make it look more presentable. It will also give me more room to write content that would other have to be dropped onto the next page. This weekend I dug up on my Latex documentation to find out how I can add a cover page. It was however no straight forward as I thought, but I found workarounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux 常用的一些命令</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/man-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/man-page/</guid>
      <description>Linux常用命令中，有些命令可以用于查看系统的状态，通过了解系统当前的状态，能够帮助我们更好地维护系统或定位问题。本文就简单介绍一下这些命令。
查看系统运行时间&amp;ndash;uptime 有时候我们想知道系统上一次复位是在什么时候或者系统已经运行了多长时间，我们可以通过uptime命令获取这些信息：
uptime 20:47:06 up 50 min, 1 user, load average: 0.75, 0.84, 0.93  从左往右显示的信息依次为：当前时间、已运行时间、用户登录数、1分钟、5分钟和15分钟内系统的平均负载。
查看系统已登录用户&amp;ndash;who who -a hyb tty7 2018-09-30 19:57 (:0)  通过who命令可以查看到哪些用户通过哪个ip登录到了这台主机。
查看系统版本相关信息&amp;ndash;uname uname -a Linux ubuntu16.04 4.15.0-34-generic #37~16.04.1-Ubuntu SMP Tue Aug 28 10:44:06 UTC 2018 x86_64 x86_64 x86_64 GNU/Linux  从结果可以看到操作系统版本（ubuntu16.04），CPU类型（x86_64）等信息
查看当前环境变量&amp;ndash;export 环境变量影响着程序的运行，因此有时候需要查看当前环境的环境变量：
export  查看目录和文件占用空间&amp;ndash;du du命令直接显示当前目录下每个目录及其文件占用空间。结合&amp;ndash;max-depth参数可以指定显示的目录层级。
例如，如果只想显示当前目录下各个目录所占总空间，可以使用:
du -h --max-depth=1 19M ./python 9.0M ./git 321M ./hexo 17M ./lua 28K ./vim 1.4M ./shell 81M .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>为什么Archlinux如此“难弄”又有何优劣？</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/archlinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/archlinux/</guid>
      <description>This is a good article that I came accross in the ArchLinux page on WeChat. It was written by Martins D. Okoi and translated by Jerry Ling/Linux中国. It has very good language and a good read for Chinese learners.
Arch Linux 于 2002 年发布，由 Aaron Grifin 领头，是当下最热门的 Linux 发行版之一。从设计上说，Arch Linux 试图给用户提供简单、最小化且优雅的体验，但它的目标用户群可不是怕事儿多的用户。Arch 鼓励参与社区建设，并且从设计上期待用户自己有学习操作系统的能力。
很多 Linux 老鸟对于 Arch Linux 会更了解，但电脑前的你可能只是刚开始打算把 Arch 当作日常操作系统来使用。虽然我也不是权威人士，但下面几点优劣是我认为你总会在使用中慢慢发现的。
1.优点： 定制属于你自己的 Linux 操作系统 大多数热门的 Linux 发行版（比如 Ubuntu 和 Fedora）很像一般我们会看到的预装系统，和 Windows 或者 MacOS 一样。但 Arch 则会更鼓励你去把操作系统配置的符合你的品味。如果你能顺利做到这点的话，你会得到一个每一个细节都如你所想的操作系统。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goat Eating at Sotik and What I Learnt That Day</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/sotik/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/sotik/</guid>
      <description>Its not everyday when someone appreiciates your hard work. The feeling that comes with this is amazing, knowing that you did your best. The trainees at our training are a wonderful lot. I was invited to one of the trainee&amp;rsquo;s home, where there was a goat eating ceremony which was organaised by the trainees. The bond and homliness that I saw there despite all of us coming from diffrent parts of the country, and different cultures was warm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/printing/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple guide on how to print on a linux machine and running Archlinux with i3.
This guide assumes that you have installed the necessay software and just wanna run a print service
To start run system-config-printer
This will produce the system dialog printing service.
Select the type of printer that you have, if its a network printer then the appropriate drivers shall be installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Kisii</title>
      <link>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/goodbye-kisii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chinese.githuka.com/blog/goodbye-kisii/</guid>
      <description>In Kisii I made new friends and the time we spent together was awesome.
Kisii was a nice place, the weather and the people. I have also learnt a few Ksii Words</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>